Variables and Functions.
変数と関数をみていきます。
Think of variables as boxes that contain
変数は情報を集めた箱だと考えてください。
information. You need a different type
違うタイプの情報には
of box for each type of information.
違うタイプの箱が必要です。
We start our variable definition
変数定義を書くときは
by saying what type of box we'd like.
初めにどのタイプ（型）の箱が必要であるか書きます。
For example, the word int
例えば、 int です。
for an integer, meaning a whole number.
これは integer のことであり、ようするに整数です。
Then we might name that box in order
次に箱を順番に名前をつけて
to identify it.
識別できるようにするかもしれません。
Then we could finish declaring that variable
次に変数の宣言を終えるために
by putting a semicolon on the end.
行末にセミコロンを置きます。
Or we can give our box some information to hold,
あるいは箱に何か格納するための情報、
for example the number 5.
例えば数字の 5 を渡します。
The first part of this is the declaration
宣言文の最初および
and the second part is the initialisation,
二つめの部分には初期化処理があります。
where the actual box gets assigned
ここでは実際の箱が割り当てられて
some information to store.
何らかの情報が格納されます。
If we want to actually do something with it,
もし実際に何かをしたい場合は
let's put it in to a function.
実際に関数に入れてみます。
As you may see when you make a new script
スクリプトを新規に作成するとき、
we're given Start and Update functions.
Start および Update 関数があらかじめ書かれています。
Start is called when the object this
Start はこのスクリプトがアタッチされたオブジェクトが
script is attached to enters a scene.
シーンに入ったときにコールされます。
We can put in Debug.log
Debug.Log を入れることで
to get the value of any variable
ゲームのあらゆる変数を取得することが出来ます。
in our game. So let's take that myInt
それでは myInt を取得して
and put it in there. If I were to just log
ここに入れてみましょう。もし単に値を
the value of that I will see it in the
ログに残すように書くと、
console in Unity. If I save that script
Unity のコンソールに出力されます。もしスクリプトを保存して
and attach it to, let's just create
オブジェクトにアタッチしてみましょう。
an empty object and assign
空のゲームオブジェクトを作成して
the script to it.
そこにスクリプトをアタッチします。
So when I press play
Play ボタンを押下すると
I see the value of myInt shown in there.
myInt の値が表示されます。
So that variable is going to maintain that
このため変数は、新しい値が与えられるまで
value until we give it a new value.
その値を保持します。
For example we could use the value of that
たとえば 変数の値を
variable with another integer.
別の整数とともに使用できます。
So here I'm multiplying by 2.
ここでは 2 を掛け算します。
So now the console will read out
これでコンソールには
that integer times by 2,
integer かける 2 を出力し、
so 5 times by 2 is 10.
今回は 5 かける 2 で 10 を表示します。
And of course if we were to reassign
当然、値をもう一回割り当てた場合
that value we will get a different
先に進むにあたり
value as we go along. So if I was
値は違ったものになります。
to say myInt=55
もし myInt = 55 とした場合
then although it was initialised
初期化されたときは
at a value of 5 this has reassigned that
5 であったものが
value to 55
55 の値を今回は割り当てられ、
and now we'll get a value of 110.
掛け算の計算を入れると値は 110 になります。
So if I save my script, press play again
このため、もしスクリプトを保存して Play ボタンを押下すると
we can see I get 110.
値は 110 が得られます。
To do something more detailed with our
より複雑なことを
boxes, or variables as they're known,
箱、すなわち変数で行なうためには、
we need to make a function,
関数を作成する必要があります。
also known as a method.
これはメソッドとも呼ばれます。
A function will take the boxes
関数は情報を格納した
that we have storing information
箱を使って
and give us boxes back,
箱を戻します。
or 'return' as it is known.
この戻すことを return といいます。
The start function that I've just put in is
ここで使用した Start 関数は
an example of a function that doesn't return
何も戻さない関数の例です。
anything. So it's type is void.
この場合の型は void といいます。
Where we make our own function we can give
カスタムの関数を作成する場合、
it a specific type of box to return.
箱にある型を決めてあげることが出来ます。
So I might say int as a type for the function,
例えば、関数の型は int であるとして、
and then give it a name. So I might
関数に名前をつけることができます。
call this function MultiplyByTwo
たとえば、2 を掛け算する関数の場合は、
because that's what it's going to do for us.
MultiplyByTwo という名前をつけます。
Then the function can have parameters.
次に、関数には引数と呼ばれるものがあります。
So we need to give a certain type
この関数には
of parameter to this function
特定の型の引数を与える必要があります。
so I'll say integer again because that's
ここでは、
the kind of information that I want to be
何かを機械に渡して戻される値の型を整数としたいので、
able to feed this machine
型は integer であると
in order to get a result back from it.
します。
Keep in mind that the inner workings of
この機械の動きは
my machine happen between these curly braces.
{} の中で行なわれることを覚えておくべきです。
So whilst the variable or
() の中のに
parameters are within round brackets
変数または引数を入れるのに対して
you'll see that the curly braces
{} により
open and close around the actions
関数の
that are in our function.
アクションを書きます。
So where I've written int number here
例えば int の数字をここに書くことは
I've effectively created a temporary
要するに Number という
variable called Number that's
機械の一部である、
part of my machine. And I'm going to
一時的な変数を作成しています。
use that in order to feed a number
これを使用して数字を
in to this function when I call upon it
この関数に渡したことになり、
in a moment. Within this machine I'm
後でコールできます。
going to create another temporary variable
この関数のなかで別の一時的な変数を作成して
and then I'm going to perform an operation
それから何らかの処理を加えます。
upon it. So I'm going to create
このため ret という
another integer called ret,
別の integer を作成します。
which is short for return. Then I'm going to
ret は return の意味の変数としています。
use that variable and say
次にこの変数を使用して
it's equal to the number variable
number 変数に 2 をかけた数字に
multiplied by 2. Then I'm going to use this
等しくします。次に return コマンドを使用して
return command so that the actual result
この関数を実際に
of running this function is that
実行して、結果は
it outputs the value of ret.
ret の値を出力します。
Once I've done that I need to actually call it
これが完了した後は、実際にコールする必要があります。
so I'm going to go back to my start function
このため Start 関数に戻って
and I'm going to call
それから
MultiplyByTwo and then instead of putting
MultiplyByTwo をコールして
a new variable in to my brackets
新しい変数を {} の中に入れる代わりに
I'm going to feed in something to be
number の中に格納する数字を
stored within number.
渡します。
So this time I'm going to feed in my int.
今回は myInt を渡します。
It will work in that because it's of the same
これで正しく動作するのは
type as the variable 'number'.
number 変数と型が同じであるためです。
So this time I'm feeding my int,
今回は myInt を渡して、
a value of 5, into my machine.
値は 5 として、機械に渡します。
It's going into the machine then ret -
機械に入って、新しい変数である
the new variable - is equal to myInt - so 5
ret は myInt に等しく、 5 かける 2
multiplied by 2, and it's returned ret.
を行なって、 ret を戻します。
So the resultant return of multiplying
このため 2 をかけて戻る結果は
by 2 will be 10.
10 となります。
But in my start function I'm simply
しかし Start 関数では
calling my MultipyByTwo function.
MultipyByTwo 関数を呼ぶだけです。
So this currently represents 10 because I'm
現時点では 5 を渡しているために
feeding in 5, multiplying by 2.
2 を掛け算をして結果は 10 となっています。
But until I do something with this information
しかし、 この情報で何かしないかぎり
no values have been changed.
値は何も変更されません。
MyInt hasn't been updated
例えば、この関数の戻り値で
with the return value of this function
myInt は更新されていません。
for example. So I could say that
では、こう書き直せば、
myInt is now equal to the result of this function.
myInt が関数の結果と等しくすることが出来ます。
And then if I actually want to see that,
それでは実際にみてみるために
I can use Debug.log
Debug.Log を使用することが出来て、
to see it printed again in the console window.
コンソールウィンドウへ再び表示できます。
So I'll save my script, switch back
それではスクリプトを保存して、元に戻したうえで
and press play and I can see a value of 10.
Play ボタンを押下すると 10 という値を見ることが出来ます。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)